翻译：小布拿拿      红豆包      斯人
翻译&校对&总监：Iz
后期：斯人     时间轴：深夏桃子
更多动画  就在@欧美动漫汉化军团
《开心汉堡店》第五季第十集
别烦我
除虫害公司
尼亚加拉蕃茄酱
Niagara ketchup!
我不明白
I don't get it.
就像尼亚加拉瀑布  但流的是蕃茄酱么
Oh, like Niagara Falls, but with ketchup?
不是  是的
No! Oh, yes.
孩子们  别闹了
Kids, stop.
你爱尼亚加拉蕃茄酱  承认吧
You love Niagara ketchup! Admit it!
-爱到想一头栽进桶里去  -没有
- You want to get in a barrel and be part of it! - No.
老爸  你还在为那个剥皮器生气吗
Dad, are you still mad about the zester?
是的  我当然生气了
Yes, of course I'm mad.
你居然用它铲吉恩鞋上的口香糖
You zested gum off Gene's shoe.
没错  这才是名副其实的好妹妹
Yeah. It's called being a good sister.
但你把它弄坏了  再也不能用它剥皮了
But now it's ruined. You can never un-zest this.
就不能再买一个吗
Can't we get another zester?
再也找不到和这个一样完美的了
Not like this one. It was perfect.
我对它满怀热情  胜过对我的人生
I had more zest for this zester than I do for life.
"zester"中的"zest"有"热情"的意思
热情似火
It was simply the zest.
老爸这么快就不行啦
Too soon.
是啊  你好  麦克
Yeah. Hey, Mike.
你有几张帐单
You got some bills,
这封信如果用力捏
and this one feels really weird
-会感觉很奇怪  -天哪
- if you squeeze it. - Oh, my God!
社区菜园寄来的
A letter from the community garden!
拜托一定要让我成为会员
Please let it say I'm accepted.
快打开  打开  打开  打开
Open it. Open it. Open it. Open it!
"亲爱的贝尔彻先生
"Dear Mr. Belcher,
我们很遗憾地通知你"  该死
we regret to inform you..." Damn it!
他们送了一包种子
Oh, they sent a packet of seeds.
安慰的种子  我也经历过
Consolation seeds. I've been there.
他们送那干嘛
Why would they send those?
不知道  蒂娜  估计是想提醒我
I don't know, Tina. I guess to remind me
这世上有个无与伦比
of the beautiful place that exists
但却不接受我的地方吧
that I'll never get to be a part of!
就像男生的衣帽间
Like the boys locker room.
或是九十年代的纽约
Or New York in the '90s!
开心些  鲍鲍  我们可以
Cheer up, Bobby. We could get you
在窗台上挂个小花盆
a little planter box to hang from the window.
这不一样  琳
It's not the same, Lin.
这不只是种点小东西
It's not just about growing a few things.
更重要的是在田间工作
It's about working the land,
为餐馆耕种食材
growing produce for the restaurant.
要是我们有院子
If we had a yard,
我就种院子里了  但我们没有
I'd do it there, but we don't.
别要求那么高
Get off your high horse.
你咋不种南瓜呢
Why don't you grow some alley pumpkins?
我想要土地
I want land!
我是个被困在餐厅老板身体里的菜农
I'm a gardener trapped in the body of an urban restaurateur.
我指甲缝里全是绞牛肉  那儿本应是
I have ground beef under my fingernails, but it should be...
绞牛肉和泥土
ground beef and dirt!
麦克  我知道你只是个邮递员
Mike, I know you're just the mailman,
但我总觉得是你动了手脚
but I can't help thinking you did this.
行啊  尽管怪我吧  我没送到你手上
Sure, blame me for this, but you never thank me
的拒绝信还有一大把呢
for the letters I don't deliver.
谢谢
Thank you.
再见
Bye-bye.
一定有办法能让我加入的
There must be something I can do to get in.
我决定了  我要去
You know what? I'm gonna walk down there
和菜园主人聊一聊
and talk to the garden master.
辛西娅啊  祝你和那贱人聊得愉快
Oh, Cynthia? Good luck with that piece of work.
是洛根的母亲辛西娅么
Cynthia as in Logan's mom?
-我的死对头洛根么  -是的
- As in Logan, my archenemy?! - Yeah.
让她转告洛根  他是个...
Tell her to tell Logan he's a... .
他的头长这样...
And his head looks like... .
脸长这样...
And his face sounds like... .
他会懂的
He'll know what it means.
我应该不会那么做  露易丝
I, uh... I probably won't do that, Louise.
要不要我写下来
Do you want me to write it down then?
好的  去吧
Yeah, go ahead.
放手去做吧  鲍鲍
You know, do what you got to do, Bobby.
就算要用和她上床来换也没关系的
If you have to sleep with her to get in, it's okay.
我不喜欢她  但能成功就行
I don't like her, but whatever it takes.
我早就想过了  琳
Way ahead of you, Lin.
简直是太完美了
It's so... perfect.
需要什么帮助吗
Can I help you?
你好  辛西娅
Oh. Hi, Cynthia.
好久不见了
So, um, uh, it's been a while
上次见还是在我的餐馆里
since we were all in my restaurant
-和那些飙车族一起  -你女儿雇的
- with all those bikers. - With all of those dirty bikers
-还接生了个婴儿  -可恶飙车族
- And that baby was born. - Your daughter hired to cut
想切掉我儿子的耳朵
off my son's ears.
-真是奇怪的一天  -没错
- Weird day! - Right!
但我们不必去回忆这件事了
But we don't... we don't have to reminisce about that.
等等  这件事
Wait. Does that have anything to do
和我被菜园拒绝有关系吗
with me not getting accepted to the garden?
当然没有了
Oh, of course not!
都是过去的事了
Bygones.
我的申请又被拒绝了
Well, my application was rejected again,
我在想是不是我表填得有问题
and I was wondering if maybe I filled it out wrong.
我的确开了点玩笑
I did make a few jokes.
比如问"你的兴趣爱好是什么"
Like where it asked, "What are your hobbies?"
我写的是"难倒我啦"
I wrote, "Beets me!"
"beat"与"beet"谐音  后者有甜菜的意思
明白了吗  拼出来是 B E E T
Get it? Spelled B-E-E-T.
洛根
Logan!
我不是故意的  我去
It was an accident! Gah!
这么热的天  他也许巴不得呢
It's hot! He probably likes it!
抱歉  鲍勃  他不是
Sorry, Bob. He's not...
我们在努力
We're working on it.
不不  他是个很好的孩子
No, no, he's a... he's a great kid.
不  他不是  但他会是的
No, he's not, but he will be.
我打算让他参加大学预科暑期项目
I'm trying to get him into this college prep summer program,
但他课外活动不够
but he doesn't have enough extracurricular activities.
比如  当志愿者么
Like, uh, volunteering?
志愿者  这年头人人都争着做
Volunteering. Everyone's doing that.
随便扔块石头
You can't throw a rock
都能砸中一个在救济院当志愿者的娃
without hitting a kid volunteering at a hospice.
我烦死那些在救济院当志愿者的娃了
Oh, I hate those kids who volunteer at hospices.
当下的热门是干无聊的工作来磨练人格
The newest thing is crappy jobs that build character.
想要出色  还得就这份工作写篇论文
You want to stand out, you write an essay about that.
什么样的工作才是无聊的工作呢
Oh. What qualifies as a crappy job?
我不知道  扫东西擦东西之类的吧
I don't know. Like sweeping stuff or mopping something.
一个可怕的地方   一份没前途的工作
You know, just some dead-end job in a horrible place.
我知道一个可怕的地方有一份没前途的工作
I know a dead-end job in a horrible place!
快来见见你们
Say hello to
社区菜园的最新成员
the newest member of the community garden!
-你好  -好啦
- Hello. - All right!
恭喜你  老爸
Congrats, Dad.
你成功了  你这个老家伙
You did it, you old son of a bitch!
再来见见我们的新员工
And say hello to our newest employee!
洛根
Logan?
不  老爸
No! Dad!
看  你们已经相处得很融洽了嘛
See? You two are already enjoying working together.
好吧  被你骗啦  是个玩笑对吧
Okay, you got me. It's a joke.
你才不会真的雇洛根
You'd never really hire Logan.
只是暂时的  露易丝
It's just temporary, Louise.
洛根的妈妈好心帮我在社区菜园
Logan's mom was nice enough to find me a plot
找了块地  条件是
at the community garden, because...
他给我这份无聊的工作
Because he gave me this crappy job.
并不无聊  别这么说
It's not crappy. Don't-don't say that.
但如果你妈妈问起来  就说很无聊
But if your mom asks, it's-it's crappy.
等等  你还要给这屁股脑袋工钱吗
Wait. You're paying this butt brain?
我屁股上的确有脑袋
My butt does have brains.
它们名叫粪便  比你聪明多了
They're called turds, and they're smarter than you.
不  是无薪实习
No, it's an unpaid internship.
我们这儿终于有点阳气了
Finally, we're getting a little more sausage at this party.
是的  吉恩
Yes, Gene.
这主意烂透了  老爸
This is a terrible idea, Dad.
这家餐馆唯一的优点就是
You've taken the only good thing about this restaurant--
没有洛根  你居然把洛根带来了
its lack of Logan-- and you added Logan!
你这话不适合在工作的地方说
That is not appropriate for the workplace.
你整个人都不适合在工作的地方出现
You are not appropriate for the workplace!
你那张脸长得和你人不合适
You're not appropriate for your face!
我打赌等你俩三十岁再联系时
I bet when you reconnect in your 30s,
你们会结婚
you guys will get married.
鲍勃  如果他们一直这么打下去
Bob, if they're gonna just fight the whole time,
他可帮不上什么忙
he's not gonna be much help.
先让他们发泄下吧
Just let them get it out of their system.
看着几乎像是在闹着玩
It's almost like they're playing.
我对他到是没什么意见
I'm okay with him.
我可以跟他请教下男生问题
I can pick his brain about mid-teen boys.
弄清到底什么才能戳中男生的笑点
Find out what tickles their pits.
真会想  蒂娜
That's a great attitude, Tina.
露易丝  我能和你去厨房谈谈吗
Louise, can I see you in the kitchen real fast?
露易丝  我真的真的很想去菜园
Louise, I really, really want this garden.
而且  这对我们所有人都有好处
Plus, it will be good for all of us.
我们可以为餐馆种新鲜的食材
We're gonna grow fresh produce for the restaurant.
-这不是很棒吗  -老爸  我才九岁
- Doesn't that sound great? - Dad, I'm nine.
还处在吐掉青菜偷藏到家里某角落的阶段
I spit out vegetables and hide them around the house.
露易丝  求你了  能不能至少试一下
Louise, please, can you at least try
和洛根和睦相处呢
and get along with Logan?
就一阵子  就当是为了我
Just for a little while? Do it for me?
-好吧  但他那次  -太好了  多谢
- Fine. But the first time he even... - Great! Thanks.
好了  我去菜园了
Okay, I'm off to the garden!
那是我的遮阳帽吗
Is that my sun hat?
是的  能借我用下吗
Yeah. Can I borrow it?
行吧  但你看起来像个英国老太太
I guess, but you look like a British lady.
我知道  多谢  再见
I know. Thanks. Bye.
我的泥土
Oh, my dirt.
我亲爱的  亲爱的  亲爱的泥土
My sweet, sweet, sweet dirt.
你好  小铲  准备大挖一场吧
Hello, trowel. You're gonna be digging.
你好  小剪
Hello, shears.
准备大剪一场吧
You're gonna be trimming.
我五年前买下你们简直太机智
I was so smart to buy you guys five years ago.
所有人都说  "你又没菜园
Everyone said, "You don't have a garden.
买园艺工具干嘛"
Why are you buying gardening equipment?"
我说  "总会有的"
And I said, "I'll grow into it."
小铲  对吗
Trowel? Right?
抱歉  我没注意
Sorry. I-I didn't see...
我以为就我一个人
I thought I was alone.
好了  洛根  同事
Okay, Logan, fellow employee,
我帮你选了这个位置
this is the spot I've chosen for you
你今天都站这儿就行了
to stand in for the rest of the day.
这儿不挡路  我们闻不到也听不到你
It's out of the way, we won't have to smell or hear you,
等下班时间一到  你就可以走人了
and when it's time to punch out, there's the door.
你会闻到我的
Oh, you're gonna smell me.
闻吧  闻闻我的体香
Smell it. Take in the aroma.
击掌
High five.
真大力
That was hard!
原来击掌这么暴力这么爽
I never knew high-fiving was so violent and satisfying!
我这只手是个男人了
My hand is a man now!
你的手是兄弟了
Your hand is a bro.
是吗  那就再来一次吧
It is? Let's bro again.
吉恩  怎么了
Gene! What?
外面都好着呢吗
Everyone getting along out there?
你懂的  琳达
You know it, Linda.
我成高空击掌俱乐部会员了
I'm in the mile-high-five club.
"高空性爱俱乐部" 俗语
指飞机机舱内的性行为
听起来不错
Sounds great.
也许是我没说清楚  洛根
Maybe I wasn't clear, Logan.
给我面对墙壁  乖乖站着  别出声
You stand in your spot, face the wall, silently,
直到下班走人
till it's time to go home,
然后就万事大吉了
and everything will be fine.
依我看来
The way I see it,
只要你爸还想去菜园
as long as your dad wants his garden,
我想干什么就干什么
I can do whatever I feel like.
-什么  -我就继续做回我刚做的事吧
- What? - Yeah. Maybe I'll go back to this.
有人点了一杯芝士吗
Oh, somebody order a cup of cheese?
一股芝士味儿
'Cause that's what it smells like.
跟我来  洛根
Come on, Logan.
我们  我们去后面
Let's-let's go in the back,
我告诉你怎么洗碗
and I'll show you how to wash the dishes.
我们  我们可以边洗碗边唠嗑
We-we can dish about the washing.
高中男生都聊些什么
So, uh, what do high school boys talk about?
第二个问题
Follow-up question.
你们是在运动完洗澡的时候聊吗
Do you talk about it in the shower after you do sports?
第三个
Additional follow-up question.
洗澡水有多烫
How hot is the water?
会有蒸汽吗
Does it produce steam?
我帮个朋友问的
I'm asking for a friend.
那是有关男人的
Yeah, that's classified,
头等机密  所以
top-secret guy stuff, so...
好吧  好吧  好吧  好吧
Right, right, right, right.
那毛巾呢  有多小
And towels, how small are they?
像洗碗布这么大吗
Like washcloth size?
更小吗
Smaller?
我来折  到差不多大你就喊停
I'll start folding this. You say when.
这样...我折不动了
Like, what... I can't even fold it more.
妈  还好吗
Hey, Mom, how you doing?
很好  洛根这事儿真值吗
Good. So, are we really sure this Logan thing is worth it?
我是说  老爸的确是家庭一员
I mean, Dad's a family member,
但充其量排第四或第五
but he's ranked, like, fourth or fifth.
露易丝  没那么糟糕
Louise, it's not that bad.
再说  你爸需要这个
Plus, your father needs this.
而且你还欠他一笔
And you owe him one.
你把他的剥皮器弄坏了
You de-zested his zester.
让他去弄菜园吧
Let him have the garden.
有时候你得学会和你讨厌的人相处
Sometimes you just got to be around people you don't like.
看看这地儿
Look at this place.
天哪  是她
Oh, God, it's her.
比我记忆中的还要糟
Oh, it's even more depressing than I remembered.
她居然敢
How dare she.
你好  琳达
Oh, hi, Linda.
我是来帮洛根写论文的
I'm just here to help Logan with his essay.
不用管我
Don't mind me.
我不会的  辛西娅
Oh, I won't, Cynthia.
你刚说什么来着  老妈
What were you saying, Mother?
关于你讨厌的人什么的
Something about people you don't like?
就当我不存在
Just pretend like I'm not here.
但能给我来杯菊花茶吗
but could I just get a chamomile tea?
抱歉  我们没那玩意
I'm sorry, we don't have that.
好吧  那就来点热水
Okay. Well, then just bring me some hot water.
一个柠檬和菊花茶
And a lemon and some chamomile tea.
对了  你没有那个
Oh, right, you don't have that.
那真是  奇怪
That's just... so weird.
好吧  有热水和柠檬就好够了
Anyway, hot water and lemon would be great.
好
Fine.
好黏
Sticky.
洛根  洛根
Logan? Logan!
-怎么了  -我开始写你的论文了
- What?! - I'm starting your essay
就说是你写的
we're gonna say you wrote!
过来扫一扫
Come out here and sweep something
好让我有东西写
so I can write about it!
晚安
Well, good night.
Good night.
鲍勃  我直说了
Okay, Bob, I'm just gonna say it.
我知道你喜欢那菜园
I know you love that garden,
但辛西娅跑来餐厅
but now Cynthia's hanging out
指指点点  还要求喝茶
at the restaurant, ordering tea.
你们好  允许我插句嘴
Hi. If I could just jump in here,
我不保证在我扇洛根之前
I don't know if I can take Logan much longer
还能忍受那货多久
before I slap that mess.
是啊  什么时候才是头啊  鲍勃
Yeah, how long is this gonna last, Bob?
大概等洛根被那暑期项目录取就行了
Probably just until Logan gets into that summer program thing,
到时我们就解放了
and then we're home free.
芝麻菜也该长熟了
Rolling in arugula.
你们就尽量无视辛西娅和洛根好了
So just try and ignore Cynthia and Logan.
扇他们就行  了解
Start slapping faces, got it.
不  不能扇  只能无视
No! No slapping. Just ignoring.
好吧  但你要知道
Fine. But just so you know,
我有这家伙和这家伙
I got this guy and this guy,
他们时刻待命
and they're ready to go to work.
看看你们
Look at you.
这才几天  都长这么大了
It's only been a few days, and you're so big!
我们知道  很快你们就要被吃掉了
We know. And soon, you'll be ready to get eaten.
什么  没什么  我什么都没说
What? Nothing. I didn't say anything.
我忘  忘了你能听懂我说英语了
I for... I forgot you could understand me, spoke English.
我要挠你们痒痒了
I'm gonna tickle you now.
不要啊  不要啊
Oh, stop! Stop!
*番茄甜豆和青豆*
*Tomatoes and sweet peas and green beans *
*梦想成真的时候*
*It's a dream come true *
*真想抓住那颗头*
*I wanna take her stupid neck *
*扭一扭*
*And wring it *
*我也想抓住那颗头  扭一扭*
*That's what I want to do, too, but with him *
*比植物更绿的是我的手指头*
*The only thing greener than these plants is my thumb *
*为何沦落至与无赖缠纠*
*How did we ever get stuck with these bums? *
*餐厅已成垃圾场*
*The restaurans now a crappy place *
*我已找到快乐天堂*
*I think I found my happy place *
*好似菜园英女郎*
*I'm like a British Lady in my garden *
*花儿赞同把头晃*
*And my plants agree *
*第一贱人给他当*
*He's the most annoying person that was ever born *
*竟然自己带茶包*
*Oh, God, she brought her own tea *
*最棒园丁长这样*
*I'm the world's greatest farmer *
*一切顺利超妥当*
*Things are growing so well *
*生活好似炼狱场*
*We're living in our own personal hell *
*餐厅已成垃圾场*
*The restaurant's now a crappy place *
*我已找到快乐天堂*
*I think I found my happy *
*餐厅已成垃圾  垃圾  垃圾*
*The restaurant's now a crappy, crappy, crappy, crappy *
*快乐  快乐  快乐*
*Happy, happy, happy, happy *
*天堂[场]*
*Place. *
小风来袭啊
Windy in here, huh?
住嘴
Stop it!
-谁该去关下们了  -住嘴
- Somebody should close the door, huh? - Stop it!
高中男生都这样  一抓一大把
High school age boys, they're a handful.
一大把这个
Handful of this.
-吉恩  -抱歉
- Gene! - Sorry.
"在这家失败的餐馆里
"These simple people were doing the best they could
那些糙人
with what little they had in their sad,
正在尽他们最大努力"
underperforming restaurant"?
别偷看
Hey, don't read that!
"糙人"
"Simple people"?
只是个说法
It's just an expression.
写文章用的
It's for the essay.
你知道吗  辛西娅
You know what, Cynthia?
不说了  为了鲍鲍  为了鲍鲍
Nope. Do it for Bobby, do it for Bobby.
一股低气压正从北边移来
We got a low-pressure system  moving in from the north
一股暖流从南边来
and a warm front moving in from the south.
臭死你
Stink-a-cane!
-混蛋  -防护
- Son of a bitch! - Take shelter!
"名不副实"是这样写的吗
Is "Slop shop" One word or two?
你知道你该写什么吗
You know what you should write about?
你的电脑被一个糙老娘们儿
A very violent event involving your computer
暴力袭击了
and a simple lady who snapped!
孩子们  去拿拖把
Kids, get a mop!
准备清扫辛西娅掉在地板上的笔记本
You're about to clean Cynthia's laptop off the floor!
太棒了  快行动
Oh, yeah. Let's do this!
小手  准备好扇人吧
Hands, time to get slappy.
搞什么啊
Wha...?
各位好啊  一切还...好吗
Hi everyone. How are things... going?
有趣但可怕
Interesting but scary.
啥事儿都没有
Everything's going great!
我正打算用脚
I was just about to proofread
帮辛西娅改论文
Cynthia's essay with my foot.
我正打算用手
And I was just gonna use my hands
给洛根的脸做个三明治
to make a Logan face sandwich.
好吧
Okay, uh, good.
嘿  辛西娅  嘿  洛根
Cynthia, hello. Logan, hey.
有些磕磕碰碰
So, uh, you know, a few bumps in the road
也是难免的
are to be expected.
这可不止是磕磕碰碰了  鲍勃
This is more than a few bumps, Bob.
这是个坏主意  跟你的菜园说再见吧
This was a bad idea. Kiss your garden good-bye.
洛根  咱们走
Logan, we're leaving!
-太好了  -棒极了
- Good! - Great!
-再见  -等  等等
- Bye. - W-wait, wait.
-你上哪儿去  -老爸  别去
- Where are you going? - Yeah, dad. Don't.
-让他们走  -我  我来处理
- Let them go. - I'll, uh... I'll handle this.
听着  我们一定能想出办法的
Look, I-I'm sure we can figure this out.
我能做点什么来补偿吗
Is-is there anything I can do to fix this?
让我做什么都可以
I-I will do anything to make this work.
我喜欢你儿子
I love your son.
看看老爸  骂了他们个狗血淋头
Look at dad. He's really laying into them.
也许我该出去支持他
Maybe I should go out there and hold him back.
还是算了
Nah, I don't think so.
熊爸爸鲍鲍
Big papa bear Bobby
帮他的熊崽子讨公道呢  好样的
looking out for his cubs. You get 'em.
真高兴洛根这场噩梦终于结束了
I'm just glad this nightmare on Logan Street is over.
我们一定有办法的
There's got to be something we can do
让你们开心
that will make you happy,
我开心  你的论文也开心
make me happy, make your essay happy.
很好  鲍勃  你把他们赶走了
All right, Bob. You told them off.
-干得好  -这个嘛
- Good job. - Yeah, well.
你听到有人在喊
Did you hear someone yelling,
"拜托  别伤害他们"了吗
"Please Hammer, don't hurt 'em"?
"Please Hammer, don't hurt'em"是说唱歌手
MC Hammer的第三张专辑名
是我喊的
That was me.
-听到了  -很好
- Yeah, yeah. - Good.
我还以为你会一直站在那蠢货那边
I thought you were gonna keep taking that doofus's side,
可我刚看到你在外面
then I saw you out there, and damn it
你真让我自豪
if you didn't make me proud.
好吧  有点小消息要和大家宣布
Okay. Um, a little news to share, everyone.
慎重考虑以后
A-after a lot of consideration,
我决定让洛根
I've decided to make Logan...
成为本月最佳员工
employee of the month.
-再说一遍  -鲍勃
- What?! - Bob!
他来这儿一周都不到
He hasn't even been here a week.
他可美了
Good for him.
听我说  露易丝
N-Now, hear me out. Louise...
你弄疼我了
You're hurting me.
鲍勃
Bob.
我的肾啊
Oh, my kidneys.
你小小个儿  力气倒蛮大的嘛
You're so small, but you're so strong.
要他还是要我  老爸
Him or me, Dad!
这是为了更高的利益  露易丝
It's for the greater good, Louise.
好吧  我知道了  没关系
Okay. I see. All right.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
我不干了
I quit!
该死  我还以为玻璃会碎
Damn it, I thought the glass would break.
无论如何  我不干了
Anyway, I quit!
玻璃没碎  给我五
The glass didn't break. High five!
鲍勃  你干的好事
Great Bobby,  great job!
露易丝可以辞职
So Louis can quit?
原来可以辞职的吗  我想辞职
Quitting is an option? I want to quit.
要不是我爱死这份工作
It would be fun to quit
辞职应该也蛮好玩的
if I didn't love this job so gosh darn much.
没人能不干  露易丝也不行
Nobody's quitting. Louise didn't quit.
她只是休息休息
She's just going on a sabbatical.
那好  我也要休息
Great. I'll do that.
不行  一年只有一次休息  吉恩
No, only one sabbatical a year, Gene.
下次轮到我
And I'm taking mine next.
没什么大不了的
This is not a big deal.
我会和露易丝谈
I'm gonna go talk to Louise.
露易丝  甜心
Louise? Sweetheart?
小甜豆
Sweet Pea?
我知道我没这么喊过你
I know I don't call you that,
不过也许我们以后可以这么喊你
but maybe we should start calling you that.
就这么定了
I'll do that.
-小甜豆  你还好么  -好极了
- Sweet Pea, how you doing in there? - Perfect!
露易丝  让洛根当月度最佳员工
Louise, making Logan employee of the month
根本不意味着什么
doesn't mean anything.
我知道  因为我们根本没评过最佳员工
I know it doesn't, because we've never done it before.
我有个好主意  让你做
Hey, I have a great idea. What if we make you
下个月的月度最佳员工如何
employee of the month next month?
我知道  理论上  蒂娜应该是下一个
I mean, Tina, technically should really be next;
她工作比你努力
she works so much harder than you.
没关系  给你搞个特例
Never mind. We'll make an exception for you.
但是蒂娜会奔溃的
But Tina will be crushed.
听上去真是棒呆了  老爸  我好期待啊
Sounds super, super great! Can't wait, Dad!
好的  我们还算谈得愉快  是吧
Okay, good. So, good talk, right?
-非常好  -开了个好头
- The best. - Good first step.
感谢参与
Thanks for participating.
爱你哦  宝贝派
Love you... Cutie Pie?
对不起  我会想个比宝贝派更好的
Sorry. I'll think of a better one than Cutie Pie.
你是我的天使粉
You're my Angel Dust.
抱歉  那是种迷幻药
Sorry, that's a drug.
我得走了  拜拜
I'm gonna go. Bye.
露易丝  你啥时候下来
Louise. When are you coming down?
你见老妈围裙脏过吗
Mom has a stain on her apron.
你错过太多啦
You're missing so much.
你怎么知道这个号码的
How'd you get this number?
老妈每天早上都写在我腿上
Mom writes it on my leg every morning
以防我走丢
in case I get lost.
我得把这儿扫扫
I better sweep this up.
你们聊你们的啊
Keep talking about whatever you're talking about.
话题不一定非得是你们正在起变化的身体
It doesn't have to be about your changing bodies,
但能聊那更好  开始
but it could be. Go.
你到底下不下来啊  我想死你了
So are you coming down or what? I miss you!
我会见到你的  吉恩
Oh I'll see you soon, Gene.
但你不会看见我
But you won't see me.
如果老爸不炒了洛根  我会让洛根
If Dad won't fire Logan, oh, I'm gonna make Logan
希望老爸从来没雇过他
wish Dad would've never hired him.
好吧  拜拜
Okay, bye.
天呐  今天应该是阴天的
Oh, my God. Today was supposed to be overcast.
不啊  今天天老好了  穿短袖的天气
No, it's a beautiful day. Shorts weather.
不不不不不
Oh, no. No, no, no.
-咋了  鲍勃  -我没盖我的豆子
- What, Bob? - I-I didn't cover my beans.
你没盖住你的豆子
You didn't cover your beans?
今天本该是阴天的
It was supposed to be overcast!
他们要死了
They're gonna die!
我得去救我的豆子
I got to save the beans!
-快去  -该死  鲍勃  你真笨
- Go! - Damn it, Bob, you're frickin' nuts.
-快去啊  -我五分钟后回来
- Go! - I'll be back in five minutes!
嘿  斯科蒂  雅各布  你们好么
Hey Scotty. Jacob. What's up?
炸薯条味道好吗  布拉赫
You liking those fries, Brah?
我请客  兄弟
On me, my friends.
我在这儿想做什么都可以
I do whatever I want around here.
因为我是本月最佳员工  所以说
'Cause I'm employee of the month, so...
搞什么  谁干的
What the... Who did that?
他妈的
Hey. Damn it.
扔个纸球而已
Just spitballin' here.
琳达  我要给他照张相
Linda, I just need one photo of him
背景得有他当最佳员工的奖状
with this employee of the month plaque in the restaurant.
或许再照几张他倒垃圾的
And maybe a few of him taking out the trash.
不如让我来把垃圾弄出去吧
why don't I take out the trash instead?
别  别  别  别  我来拍照的
Bup, bup, bup, bup. I-I'm taking the photo.
滚  滚  滚  滚  不给拍
Dup, dup, dup, dup. No, you don't.
-鲍勃和我说好的  -说的就是不让你拍
- Bob and I have a deal. - Deal with this, honey.
-艾玛  我的脸  -我的脸
- Oh, my face! - Ow, my face!
弄好了  你们没事吧  对吧
Okay, we're good. You guys are good, right?
谢谢你  鲍勃  我们本来又热又害怕
Thanks, Bob. We were hot and scared.
-亏待你们了   -给我们讲个笑话吧
- Oh, I'm sorry, guys. - Tell us a joke.
不行  我得回去了
No, I-I... I got to get back.
求你了  就讲一个
Please? Just one?
好吧  一个哦
All right, just one.
一个小孩在沙盒里玩
A kid's playing in a sandbox
他找到一个电焊面罩
and he finds a welding mask.
不  等下  还  还没讲完
No, wait, there... that's not the end.
后面还有
It's more.
有个小孩在沙盒里玩
Okay, a kid's playing in a sandbox.
谁在用纸球扔我
Who's hitting me with spitballs?!
隐形纸球忍者么
Invisible spitball ninja.
洛根  你脸上有东西
Logan, you got something on your face right there.
-住手  -那里也有
- Stop it! - Oh, and also right there.
露易丝  我知道是你
Louise, I know it's you.
你躲哪儿了
Where are you?
我在你心里  洛根
I'm in your mind, Logan.
这里好宽敞的
There's a lot of room in here.
我一定会找到你的
Oh, I'm gonna find you.
我不会放过你
And I'm gonna get you.
我...
And I'm gonna...
我的小舌
My uvula!
大嘴员工
Employee of the mouth!
琳达  管管你女儿
Linda, control your daughter!
好消息  青豆没事儿
Good news. The green beans are doing all right.
你和你的菜园呐
Oh, you and that garden.
你一身的土味儿和新鲜空气味儿
You smell like dirt and fresh air.
真恶心
And it makes me sick!
还有  你女儿抓狂了
Your daughter's gone nuts, by the way.
她这会儿正躲在通风口冲人扔纸球呢
She's in the crawlspace shooting spitballs at everybody.
-露易丝  快出来  -不要
- Louise, get out of there. - No!
除非你炒掉洛根
Not until you fire Logan.
露易丝  你给我马上出来
Hey. Louise, you come out of there right now.
是你逼我的
I don't want to do this,
你别想当下月的最佳员工了
but you're not gonna be the next employee of the month;
你被排到最后了
you're gonna be the last employee of the month,
连吉恩都在你前面  抱歉  吉恩
even after Gene! Sorry, Gene.
干嘛道歉  我没在听诶
Sorry for what? I wasn't listening.
而且我不会炒洛根
And I'm not gonna fire Logan;
我要继续留在菜园
I'm keeping the garden,
你自己看着办吧  露易丝
and you're gonna deal with it, Louise,
这对我们大家都好
because it's good for all of us.
你不让我提削皮刀的事儿了么
And not to bring up the zester again,
我就要提  你欠我的
but the zester. You owe me.
我告诉你吧
And let me tell you something.
在菜园里度过的时间
Spending time in the garden has helped me
让我明白了几件事
realize a few things.
我们得多出去走走  知道吗
We need to go outside more, okay?
应该多散步
Why don't we go on walks?
大家都该这样
As a whole society?
大家都该步行出门
People should go out on walks!
都该去种菜
And people should garden!
鲍勃  抱歉打断你的演说
Bob? I hate to interrupt your flow.
你讲得不错  不错
Great speech though, great speech.
是啊  越听越有道理
Yeah, it really got going after a while.
-老爸  -怎么了
- Dad? - Yes?
我们不会真的步行出门吧
We're not going on walks, are we?
我不知道  也许吧
I don't know. Maybe.
总之  就在你对着墙说话的时候
Anyway, while you were talking to the wall,
露易丝溜进来带走了你的园艺剪刀
Louise snuck in and took off with your gardening shears.
-什么  -她看起来跃跃欲试呢
- What? - Yeah. She looked ready to use them, too.
不知道她想用它干嘛
I wonder on what.
用它剪啥呢
What could it beans?
天呐  我的菜园
Oh, my God, my garden!
露易丝  别这样  好吗
Louise, just stop, okay?
我知道  你生气了
I get it, you're mad.
我要抽筋儿了
Also, I'm getting a cramp.
别啊  赶紧停下来舒展舒展
Oh, no! Better stop and stretch it out!
露易丝  你现在拿着剪刀狂奔呢
Louise, you're literally running with scissors.
一把超大的剪刀
Really big scissors.
我知道  感觉真好
I know, it feels great!
太好了  关门了
Oh, good, it's closed.
露易丝  结束了
Louise, it's over!
我们回家吧
Come on, let's go home.
我去
Oh, crap.
天  你怎么这么小
God, how small are you?
和你的烂植物说再见吧
Say good-bye to your crappy crops.
没那个必要
Don't have to.
你又不知道哪块地是我的
You don't know which plot is mine, Louise.
该不会是插着纸板标志  上面写着
Is it the one with the paper plate sign
"鲍勃的小美人"的这块吧
that says Bob's Beauties?
不...是
No.
别别别
No, no, no, no.
你...露易丝  你没必要这样
You... Louise, you don't have to do this!
你也没必要请洛根
You didn't have to hire Logan either.
露易丝  求你了  那可是我的宝贝啊
Louise, please. Those are my babies.
啥  这些么  它们是你的宝贝
What? These. These are your babies?
是的  那些是...
Yes. Those are...
我怎么会当着我孩子的面
Yeah. Why did I... say that
说出那样的话
in front of my actual baby?
是的
Yeah!
好吧  也许关于菜园的事
Right. Yeah, so maybe this whole
我是有点太自私了
garden thing was a little selfish.
我终于明白  更高的利益
Yeah, I noticed how the greater good
就是尽情做自己想做的事
meant doing the thing you like to do.
你说得对
You're right. You know what?
动手吧  都剪了吧
Do it. Cut them. Cut them down.
-什么  真的吗  -动手吧
- What? Really? - Yeah, do it.
我罪有应得  我还是不看了
I deserve it. I can't watch.
我没办法  不是它们的错
I can't. It's not their fault.
说得对  是我的错
That's right. It's my fault.
-那我就剪你吧  -什么
- So I'm gonna cut you. - What?
开个玩笑
Just kidding.
我知道
I know.
抱歉我请了洛根
Look, I'm sorry I hired Logan.
我知道你很不喜欢他
I-I know how much you don't like him.
是的  我公开表示很多次了  老爸
Yeah, I'm pretty open about that, Dad.
而且  餐馆是我们的地盘
Plus, I mean, the restaurant is our place.
我希望它能一直那样
And I like it that way.
我知道  算是知道吧
I know you do.  I mean, sort of.
我曾经怀疑过
I had a suspicion.
因为你感情隐藏得很好
But you do hide it pretty well.
-多谢  -抱歉我醉心于小甜豆
- Thank you. -I'm sorry I put my sweet peas
把我真的"小甜豆"给忽略了
before my Sweet Pea.
-你习惯这个昵称了吗  -没有
- Is that nickname thing working at all now? - No.
那你能先原谅我吗
Can you forgive me anyway?
有一个条件
Under one condition.
-你被炒了  -什么
- You're fired! - What?
她不能炒我  对吗
She can't fire me. Right?
当然不能
Of course she can't.
我看她刚就炒了
Yeah, I think she just did.
露易丝现在是我们人力资源部的了
Louise is actually our human resources person now.
而我是新业务的执行总经理
And I'm executive vice president of new business!
天呐  就我还在擦桌子呢
Oh, man, I've just been bussing tables.
洛根  如果你需要建议  听好了
Logan, if you need a recommendation, here's one:
给脸上罩个袋子吧
put a bag on your face.
我会在你脸上罩一个的
I'll put a bag on your face.
好了  亲爱的  我得让保安请你出去了
Okay, hon, I'm gonna have security walk you out now.
-我不  -鲍勃  希望你有
- No. - Well, I hope you enjoyed
好好珍惜最后一趟菜园之旅
your last trip to the garden, Bob.
你以后别想再去了
Because it was your last trip.
我知道  所以我才把所有植物
I know. That's why I dug up all my plants
都挖回家了
and brought them home.
-我还借用了你的手推车  -我的..
- And I used your wheelbarrow. - My...
谁允许你用的
You're not allowed to use that.
用都用了
It already happened.
你拿我也没辙啊
There's nothing you can do about it.
我还撬开了你大门的锁
And I broke the lock on your gate.
我会给你换一个的
Which I will replace.
你也该把你的茄子给换一换了
Which is what you should do with your eggplant.
看着好娇小
It looks leggy.
-洛根  我们走  -你们都疯了
- Logan, let's go. - You're all nuts.
你要是愿意把你的邮箱地址告诉我
so if you want to shoot me your e-mail,
我可以把我剩下有关的男生问题发给你
I can just send you the rest of my boy questions.
才不要
Absolutely not.
才不要@  啥邮箱
"Absolutely not" At what .Com?
拜  辛西娅
Bye, Cynthia.
我往你的笔记本电脑上泼了水
I spilled water on your laptop.
她没听到  但她会发现的
She didn't hear me. She'll figure it out.
感觉有点挤啊
Looking a little cramped.
是啊  我们也许应该只种一株的
Yeah, we probably should've just planted one.
-不  -天呐
- Oh, no! - Oh, God!
*番茄甜豆和青豆*
*Tomatoes and sweet peas and green beans *
*梦想成真的时候*
*It's a dream come true *
*真想抓住她的头  扭一扭*
*I want to take her stupid neck and ring it *
*我也想抓住他的头  扭一扭*
*That's what I want to do, too, but with him *
*比植物更绿的是我的手指头*
*The only thing greener than these plants is my thumb*
*怎会沦落至*
*How did we ever get *
*与无赖缠纠*
*Stuck with these bums? *
*餐厅已成垃圾场*
*The restaurant's now a crappy place *
*我已找到快乐天堂*
*I think I found my happy place *
*好似菜园英女郎*
*I'm like a British lady in my garden, and my... *